[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "‘Please write to me at the above address’. The word ‘above’ in this sentence is a/an-",
    "options": ["noun", "adjective", "pronoun", "adverb"],
    "answer": "adjective"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "In which sentence is the word ‘past’ used as a preposition?",
    "options": [
      "Tania was a wonderful singer, but she’s past her prime.",
      "Writing letters is a thing of the past",
      "I look back on the past without regret",
      "I called out to him as he ran past"
    ],
    "answer": "Tania was a wonderful singer, but she’s past her prime."
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "The word ‘sibling’ means-",
    "options": ["a brother", "a brother or sister", "a sister", "an infant"],
    "answer": "a brother or sister"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "Fill in the blank: As she was talking, he suddenly broke __, saying, ‘That’s a lie!’",
    "options": ["off", "down", "in", "into"],
    "answer": "in"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "Fill in the blank: You may go for a walk if you feel ___ it.",
    "options": ["like", "about", "on", "for"],
    "answer": "like"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Identify the word which is spelt incorrectly:",
    "options": [
      "perseverance",
      "convalescence",
      "maintenance",
      "consciencious"
    ],
    "answer": "consciencious"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "‘You look terrific in that dress!’ The word ‘terrific’ in the above sentence means-",
    "options": ["funny", "very ugly", "horrible", "excellent"],
    "answer": "excellent"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "someone who is capricious is-",
    "options": [
      "easily irritated",
      "wise and willing to cooperate",
      "known for sudden changes in attitude or behaviour",
      "exceedingly conceited and arrogant"
    ],
    "answer": "known for sudden changes in attitude or behaviour"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "Which one of the following words is masculine",
    "options": ["mare", "pillow", "lad", "pony"],
    "answer": "lad"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "A man whose wife has died is called a ---",
    "options": ["widow", "widower", "spinster", "bachelor"],
    "answer": "widower"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "Which word is similar to ‘appal’ ?",
    "options": ["deceive", "dismay", "confuse", "solicit"],
    "answer": "dismay"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "Which word means the opposite of ‘dearth’ ?",
    "options": ["abundance", "lack", "poverty", "shortage"],
    "answer": "abundance"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "Indentify the word which remains the same in its plural form:",
    "options": ["intention", "mouse", "aircraft", "thesis"],
    "answer": "aircraft"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "Identify the determiner in the following sentence: ‘I have no news for you.’",
    "options": ["have", "news", "for", "no"],
    "answer": "no"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "‘A lost opportunity never returns.’ Here ‘lost’ is a __",
    "options": ["gerund", "participle", "verbal noun", "gerundial infinitive"],
    "answer": "participle"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "The saying 'enough is enough' is used when you want-",
    "options": [
      "something to stop",
      "something to continue",
      "something to continue until it's enough",
      "to tell instructions are clear"
    ],
    "answer": "something to stop"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "‘He ran with great speed.’ The underlined part of the sentence is a -",
    "options": [
      "noun phrase",
      "adjective phrase",
      "participle phrase",
      "adverb phrase"
    ],
    "answer": "adverb phrase"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "‘We must not be late, else we will miss the train.’ This is a -",
    "options": [
      "complex sentence",
      "simple sentence",
      "compound sentence",
      "interrogative sentence"
    ],
    "answer": "compound sentence"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "Change the voice: ‘Who is calling me?’",
    "options": [
      "By whom am I being called?",
      "By whom am I called?",
      "By whom I am called?",
      "Whom am I called by?"
    ],
    "answer": "By whom am I being called?"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "An extra message added at the end of a letter after it is signed is called-",
    "options": ["postscript", "NB", "corrigendum", "RSVP"],
    "answer": "postscript"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "‘The Rape of the Lock’ by Alexander Pope is a/an-",
    "options": ["epic", "ballad", "elegy", "mock-heroic poem"],
    "answer": "mock-heroic poem"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "Which of the following is not an American poet?",
    "options": [
      "Robert Frost",
      "W. B. Yeats",
      "Emily dickinson",
      "Langston Hughes"
    ],
    "answer": "W. B. Yeats"
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "William Shakespeare was born in -",
    "options": ["1616", "1664", "1564", "1493"],
    "answer": "1564"
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "Tennyson’s ‘In Memoriam’ is an elegy on the death of-",
    "options": [
      "Arthur Henry Hallam",
      "John Milton",
      "John Keats",
      "Sydney Smith"
    ],
    "answer": "Arthur Henry Hallam"
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "‘Sweet Helen’ make me immortal with a kiss.’ The sentence has been taken from the play-",
    "options": [
      "Romeo and Juliet",
      "Caesar and Cleopatra",
      "Doctor Faustus",
      "Antony and Cleopatra"
    ],
    "answer": "Doctor Faustus"
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "‘What’s in a name? That which we call a rose By any other name would smell as sweet’- Who said this?",
    "options": ["Romeo", "Portia", "Rosalind", "Juliet"],
    "answer": "Juliet"
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "‘Man’s love is of man’s life a thing apart, ‘Tis woman’s whole existence.’- This is taken from the poem of-",
    "options": ["P. B. Shelley", "Lord Byron", "John Keats", "Edmund Spenser"],
    "answer": "Lord Byron"
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "question": "Who translated the ‘rubaiyat of Omar Khayyam’ into English?",
    "options": [
      "Thomas Carlyle",
      "D. G. Rossetti",
      "Edward Fitzgerald",
      "William Thackeray"
    ],
    "answer": "Edward Fitzgerald"
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "question": "‘Ulysses’ is a novel written by-",
    "options": [
      "James Joyce",
      "Joseph conrad",
      "Thomas Hardy",
      "Charles Dickens"
    ],
    "answer": "James Joyce"
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "question": "The short story ‘The Diamond Necklace’ was written by-",
    "options": [
      "Guy de Maupassant",
      "Somerset Maugham",
      "O Henry",
      "George Orwell"
    ],
    "answer": "Somerset Maugham"
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "question": "‘All the perfumes of Arabia will not sweeten this little hand.’- Who said this?",
    "options": ["Macbeth", "Lady Macbeth", "Lady Macduff", "Macduff"],
    "answer": "Lady Macbeth"
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "question": "‘Where are the songs of Spring? Aye, where are they? Think not of them, thou hast thy music too’.- Who wrote this?",
    "options": [
      "William Wordsworth",
      "Robert Browning",
      "Samuel Coleridge",
      "John Keats"
    ],
    "answer": "John Keats"
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "question": "Who is the central character of ‘Wuthering Heights’ by Emily Bronte?",
    "options": ["Heathcliff", "Mr. Earnshaw", "Catherine", "Hindley Earnshaw"],
    "answer": "Heathcliff"
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "question": "‘The old order changeth, yielding place to new.’- This line is extracted from Tennyson’s poem-",
    "options": [
      "The Lotos-Eaters",
      "Morte d’ Arthur",
      "Tithonus",
      "Locksley Hall"
    ],
    "answer": "Morte d’ Arthur"
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "question": "Who wrote the poem ‘The Good-Morrow’?",
    "options": [
      "George Herbert",
      "Andrew Marvell",
      "John Donne",
      "Henry Vaughan"
    ],
    "answer": "John Donne"
  }
]
